Finding Aid for Dale R. Leslie papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dale R. Leslie collection 1941-2013 2008-2013
Leslie, Dale R., collector
9577 Aa 2 UAm
Ann Arbor, Mich. resident and businessman with strong interest in local history. Collection includes video featuring interviews with residents and other historical footage of landmarks and events in Ann Arbor, Ypsilanti, and the hamlet of Dixboro as well as collected papers and records related to Ann Arbor High School and Dixboro United Methodist Church.
0.4 linear feet
8.25 GB online
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Dale R. Leslie (donor no. 6874 ) in various accessions from 2006-2014.
Periodic additions to the papers expected.
The collection is open to research. The collection is open without restriction. Due to copyright, some digital sound recordings are only available in the reading room of the Bentley Historical Library.
Dale Leslie, a life-long Ann Arborite, is an active local history steward and community volunteer in the greater Ann Arbor, Michigan area. Leslie earned master's degrees from Ohio University and the University of Michigan as well as a bachelor's degree from Eastern Michigan University. From 1961-1997, Leslie owned and operated Leslie Office Supply, Inc. The business was sold in 1997.
Leslie has been active in several Ann Arbor area community groups. Leslie is on the board of directors for the Washtenaw County Historical Society, a member and former president of the Kiwanis Club of Ann Arbor, a former executive committee member of the Ann Arbor Area Chamber of Commerce, a former member of the City of Ann Arbor Cable Communications Commission, and a member of the Ann Arbor First Presbyterian Church.
The Dale R. Leslie papers collection is comprised of two series: Michigan History and Interviews.
Most of the collection consists of digitized film footage and digital video relating to Ann Arbor and Michigan history.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Ann Arbor High School (Mich.)--Football.; Ann Arbor High School (Mich.). Class of 1966.; Autism--Michigan.; Big Ten Conference (U.S.)--Songs and music.; Dixboro (Mich.)--Church history.; Dixboro (Mich.)--History.; Dixboro United Methodist Church (Dixboro, Mich.)--History.; Leslie, Dale R.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Detroit.; Superior (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township)--History.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--History.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Air shows--Michigan.; Ann Arbor High School (Mich.); Students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Dixboro United Methodist Church (Dixboro, Mich.); Big Ten Conference (U.S.)
Genre Terms:
Digital moving image formats.; Sound recordings.
- Michigan History
  The Michigan History series (3 folders and 4.44 GB) includes images, recordings, and interviews on the subject of local history, events, and landmarks. It is divided into three subseries according to geographic locations covered by the material: Ann Arbor, Detroit, and Dixboro and Superior Township.
  The Ann Arbor History subseries (1 folder, 3GB) includes various video and paper materials related to events and people from Ann Arbor. It also contains a program and a commemorative video recording from the 50 year reunion of the 1962 state champion Ann Arbor High School football team. Also included is footage of the building of Ann Arbor High School in the 1950s, the memorial service for University of Michigan athletic standout Don Lund, and videos of various individuals who spoke at local Kiwanis Club meetings.
  The Detroit History subseries (1 folder, 0.8GB) consists of one digitized CD audio called Motor City Radio Reunion.
  The Dixboro and Superior Township History subseries (1 folder, 0.64GB) consists of several informative videos and a recorded speeches about the history of Dixboro, particularly the Dixboro United Methodist Church. Also included is a silent film, with new narration by Dale Leslie, from 1941 called Sweet Genevieve.
  - Ann Arbor
    - Ann Arbor High School Football 50 Year Reunion
      - Program and other items 2012 (Box 1)
      - 1962 Seadon Highlights (video recording), 1962, .MP4 file
    - Dale R. (for "Radio") Leslie Presents Big Ten Medley, undated, .ZIP file
    - Building Ann Arbor High School, 1953-56, .MOV file
    - Don Lund Memorial Service 2013, .MP4 file
    - Memorial Day Tribute 2013, .MP4 file
    - Michigan Radio (WUOM) Highlights 2013, .MOV file
    - Kiwanis Club of Ann Arbor Presentations
      - Art Holst (Former NFL official) 2011, .M4V file
      - Neal Boudette (Wall Street Journal Detroit Bureau Chief) 2012, .M4V file
      - Sheriff Harvey: "The Michigan Murders," 2011, .M4V file
    - Columns from Ann Arbor magazines and newspapers, 1999-2008 (Box 1)
  - Detroit History
    - Motor City Radio Reunion, 2010, .ZIP file
      [Download access restricted to BHL Reading Room]
  - Dixboro and Superior Township
    - Dixboro United Methodist Church
      - Speeches 1983 (cassette tape) (Box 1)
      - Sesquicentennial 2008, .MP4 file
    - Dixboro School, Centennial Observance 1988, .MP4 file
    - Sanderson, Harvey (speech) 1982, .MP4 file
    - Sweet Genevieve, 1941, .MOV file
    - Tour of Dixboro 1989, .MP4 file
- Interviews
  The Interviews series (1 folder, 3.84GB) features interviews performed or collected by Dale Leslie. The interviewees are members of the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Brighton and Ypsilanti communities.
  - Austin: Autism Personified, 2007, .MP4 file
  - Fletcher, Peter B. 2008, .MP4 file
  - Recollections of the Ann Arbor Air Force, 2009, .MOV file
  - Renfrew, Al 2012, .MOV file
  - Staebler, Don (Living a Legacy) 2011, .M4V file
  - Stegath, Dr. William B. 2011, .MOV file
  - Willis, Dr. Edgar E. 2013, .MOV file
  - Woinowsk, Russ undated, .MP4 file